[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
Lily's been through so much.
This won't take her down.
You're going to die. Poor, Ivy.
I am Ivy Aguas. I can handle everything.
[laughing]
-Hello, Dad?
-Where are you? I'll help you.
We're going to save Ivy
no matter what happens.
[Damian] I'm here to help Ivy Aguas.
[gunshots]
[Camia] She still has to bring
those criminals to justice.
[Julio] You have been sleeping
with the enemy.
Your enemy, Governor. Not mine.
[Diego] We won't give up.
We'll keep fighting and remove
Julio Ardiente from power.
We can't let my daughter's
sacrifices be for nothing.
Well, good luck to your endeavors,
Diego Torillo.
All your efforts will be in vain.
[crowd chanting] Cheater!
Come on, Emilia.
[chuckling nervously]
This is not happening. Come on.
[Ivy] Mark my words, Emilia.
If I die, I will haunt you.
[screaming]
Raul! Papa!
-Papa!
-Hey! Hey! What?!
-What?
Papa. Papa.
We need to have this house blessed
or start practicing feng shui, Papa.
What's wrong with this house?
Hold on. Didn't you have this place
blessed before moving in?
-No. But…
-Why?
[Julio] Look, look.
There is only one bad spirit
that's in this house right now,
and that is the cheap beer
that Raul is drinking.
Papa, I'm not joking! I saw a ghost!
I saw Ivy Aguas there!
I saw her there! I'm not joking!
Raul, please believe me!
Papa, I saw her there.
She was so close to me.
I could even smell her.
All right, enough, enough.
I bet it's all in your head.
-No! It's not!
-I say, Emilia, grow up.
There are no such things as ghosts.
No, Papa! You have to trust me this time!
I saw her! I saw Ivy Aguas there, Papa!
This is real. There really is a ghost.
She's haunting me.
Papa, she's haunting me.
You know what? This only means one thing.
That Ivy Aguas is truly dead.
And, if she's ever going to haunt someone,
[chuckling] it's definitely you.
No, Papa. No! No! No!
-Who's in there?!
-[screaming]
-[laughing]
Papa. [wailing]
[howling]
-[Julio] Whoo!
-I hate you both!
[Julio chuckles]
Ma'am?
Ma'am!
I hate you! I hate you!
-What the--
-I hate you!
Stop it. Hold on.
[grunting]
-What is your problem?
-You.
You're my problem.
You tossed me aside.
You used me.
You took my men and my weapons
just so you could help
your worthless friends.
You're all the same.
And here I thought you were different.
You're another user!
You're so emotional.
You're overthinking things.
Just let me explain.
Yes, you're right.
I went out to help my friends.
I went out to look for Ivy Aguas.
But if you really want
to take the Ardientes down…
then, believe me,
we're going to need their help.
They're on our side.
So, where's your
amazing friend, Ivy Aguas?
I thought she wanted to be a superhero?
Well? What now?
She's dead.
She's dead!
[exhales]
I'm warning you, Madrigal.
Forget about those friends of yours.
Because I'm the only one who can help you.
[tense music playing]
[exhales]
Come on, Emilia. Don't be scared.
She's already dead.
She can't even hurt you.
She's dead. Just get a grip, Emilia!
Come on, come on, come on.
Inhale, exhale. You can do it.
It's time to sleep.
[exhales]
-[glass breaks]
-[gasps]
[eerie music playing]
[loud thud]
Did you hear that?
That's it, Governor. Fifty million pesos.
Good.
So, who do you plan to give it to?
That is for our dear Martel.
So he can forget about our little deal
during the election.
Count it as insurance.
Can't be too careful.
He might just rat us out.
Especially now that these two birds,
by the name of Torillo and Ruiz,
are teaming up against me.
So it's true, Governor?
That they really can oust you
from your position?
Oust? Julio Ardiente?
[laughing]
Impossible.
The votes have been counted.
And I've been declared the winner.
Remember, I know politics
like the back of my hand.
Now, the only thing I hate,
Colonel, is all that fussing
while we plan
for the centennial celebration.
I'm sure you know the whole
province is watching us.
So, let's take advantage
of this opportunity.
It's a chance to clear up our image
and make sure our enemies
don't tarnish it again.
I'll go ahead, Governor.
All right. Be careful with that.
Yes, Governor.
[thudding]
[eerie music playing]
[screaming]
Who are you? Oh my God! Who are you?
[whimpering]
Ivy! Oh my God!
Hi, Emilia!
No! You cannot do this to me!
No! You're already dead!
But if I'm already dead, Emilia,
why am I still stuck in your head?
No! You can't hurt me, Ivy,
because you're dead!
You can't do this to me!
-That's what you think.
-No! No!
-Bye, Emilia!
-No! No! No! No!
-I'm going to miss you.
-No!
-Don't die, Emilia!
-Don't leave me, Emilia.
-No! Ivy, no!
You can't do this!
No!
[gasping]
[exhales]
[car engine stops]
[car door opens]
[somber music playing]
[car door closes]
[somber music continues]
[Ivy] Bastards!
All of you!
[screaming]
Bastards!
From now on,
you are not getting inside my head.
Because dead people belong in the grave.
And, you are dead.
Dead. Dead. Dead!
[sighs]
[somber music continues]
[alarm clock ringing]
[ringing stops]
[instrumental theme music playing]
Thank you, Lily.
[Jepoy] Anna?
What's that?
Who's it from?
[music continues]
-Loring. Loring, come here.
-What?
Look at what's on our table. Quick!
What is it?
[Loring] Oh. What is it?
[woman] It's beautiful. Who's it from?
Emma! Emma!
Look at this! Come here, quick!
-What's happening here?
-Where is it from?
The flower is so beautiful.
-You have one too?
-Yeah.
-It's beautiful.
-Looks like everyone got one.
-Smells nice.
-You have one too?
-It smells nice.
-We all have one.
-Where are they from?
-Who do you think they're from?
Emma, who are these from?
-I don't know.
-How did they get here?
-Yeah.
-They got a flower too.
-We all did.
-Where are these from?
-Yeah.
-Oh, it's beautiful.
-Smell it. It smells nice.
-It really smells nice.
-Who are these from?
-Look at it.
-It makes you wonder.
[music continues]
[no audible dialogue]
[music fades]
[suspenseful music playing]
J-Jenny!
Jenny! Jenny!
-Ma'am?
-Who's this from?
Who left that here?!
-Ma'am, I don't know.
-Who's this from?
Get that thing away from me!
Throw it away! Right now!
Emilia, your mansion's
feng shui is beautiful.
The positioning of the pool
and the seats are perfect.
Everything's perfect.
What about my political career?
I can see that your political star
and your career
will be wonderful this year.
I can see your father
handing you a good position.
-Really?
-Yes. Let's see.
-How about my love life?
-You have two love stars.
You will attract two men this year.
-Two?
-Two men.
Hmm… That's exciting, huh?
What more can you tell me, Master?
How about, um, this house?
Are the vibes good?
Yes. The feng shui
of this house is beautiful.
-[Julio] Is the car ready?
-Luck is good in this house.
Wait. Here is my Papa.
-Papa.
-Yes?
I'd like you to meet Master Hanz Cua.
-Good afternoon.
-Governor Ardiente.
Good Afternoon, Master Hanz Cua.
-Good afternoon, Mr. Governor.
-I've heard about you. Yes.
-Yes, sir.
-Ah, I have to go.
Papa, where are you going?
We have technical rehearsals later.
I have some things to attend to.
I'll leave you here with the Master.
Sort out all the feng shui you want.
Um, excuse me.
Papa, can I ask you something?
Um, you know, now that Ivy Aguas is gone,
-Mm-hm.
-…are you still keeping your
promise?
Oh! Yeah, yeah, my promise. Don't worry.
I'm going to get back at that
Vice Governor Ruiz
for trying to oust me.
I will strip him of his position
and give it to you.
[exclaims] Thank you, Papa!
Oh, my gosh! Thank you, Papa.
And I am really, really sorry
for doubting you.
And I really apologize
for everything, Papa.
And thank you for giving me
this second shot in my life, Papa.
-Thank you so much, Papa.
-Yeah.
I have to go. I have to go.
[Julio grunts]
Master, did you hear what Papa said?
-Yes, I did.
-You're so good.
He's going to give me back
my position as vice governor.
Yes.
So, when I become the vice governor
and then he becomes too old,
I'll be the governor.
-That's right.
-I knew it!
This is really my year.
-Yes.
-Let's go around some more.
-Okay. I'll check.
-Come. I'll give you a bonus.
Here. How about this painting?
Is it unlucky?
Do you know what you're
getting yourself into?
I do.
I wouldn't come here if I didn't.
I have strong evidence
against Julio Ardiente.
Congressman, if you really want to win,
you have to make the investment.
I'm sure you'll earn back
whatever you invested
once you're governor, correct?
I'm only one call away, Congressman.
One call away from your victory.
[chuckles]
Well, it looks like you have
everything figured out.
But the thing is, people who complain
about the election start out determined.
After a while, they lose their focus.
Their interest.
Others are even murdered
by the opposition…
to silence them.
[scoffs]
-Are you threatening me?
-Of course not.
I'm just telling the truth.
I'm not afraid.
I have the vice governor's support.
And I'm not the only one
against Julio Ardiente.
There's someone more powerful.
Someone more powerful
who's against your politics.
Who?
[tense music playing]
Commissioner, thank you
very much for your time.
[woman] Good morning, Governor.
Good morning.
[chuckles]
Of course.
Anytime.
-[man] Good morning, Governor.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Governor.
[tense music continues]
Commissioner?
[stammering] Governor,
I wasn't expecting you.
-Please, have a seat.
-Okay. Thank you.
[grunts]
Master Hanz, come on.
Feel free to roam around.
This is our dining.
Uh, Madam, should I dispose of these?
Wait, let me check.
I miss you, Aunt Claire.
[pensive music playing]
Throw these out, and get out of my face.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia] Please, don't!
Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't!
Who ordered you to kidnap me?
Who?! Answer me!
You won't stay here long, Mrs. Torillo.
We'll take you to Poblacion Ardiente
as soon as possible.
[line ringing]
Romulo?
Who is this?
Why do you have Claire's phone?
It's me, Emilia.
Listen carefully, Emilia.
Don't let Julio Ardiente get
a hold of Claire's belongings,
especially not her phone.
Why? Aren't you one of Papa's men?
I don't work for the Ardientes.
If you're not one
of Papa's men, who are you?
Wasn't it Papa who helped me
get out of jail?
Your father?
He's the one who had you imprisoned.
He didn't save you.
He wasn't the one who helped you.
What?
[stutters] Papa didn't have
my case dismissed?
If not him, then who?
-Who?!
-[call dropped]
[line busy]
Oh, come on! What's with everyone today?!
[line ringing]
Hello? We need to talk.
As agreed upon,
here's your 50 million pesos.
And there's an additional 10 million…
for helping me win this election.
Governor, you know that I don't
always give out favors
to public officials who ask for my help.
I know that very well, Mr. Martel.
I know that you stick with
only the most powerful ones.
Because power is more important
than money,
especially when that money runs out.
Very true.
Diego Torillo and Mateo Ruiz
aren't the only ones
you have to deal with.
Someone else has filed
a complaint against you.
[scoffs]
Who?
Who else dared to go up against me?
Lily Cruz.
[tense music playing]
[Anna] Jepoy?
Anna.
Jepoy, what are you doing here?
Why didn't you join the others?
I'm here to protect you.
I swore to myself and to Ivy that I would.
Anna, we have a problem.
You will be Julio's next target
when he finds out
the name of the person
who wants to overthrow him.
[Julio] Lily Cruz?
Lily Cruz is nothing.
Well, Governor, I have to tell you.
At this point, in my opinion,
Lily Cruz is a viable option.
Lily Cruz has got no power.
She's got no money.
Governor, I hope you understand.
In my position,
I have to be open to the highest bidder.
I have to be willing to entertain
all those who come to me.
If it's money you need,
all you need to do is ask.
If I double the amount I'm giving you,
would that make you stop
entertaining those pesky insects
buzzing in your ear?
How about it, Mr. Martel?
[phone ringing]
Jepoy, I can take care of myself.
You should go to whoever it is
that's calling you.
Forget about that, Anna.
You're more important to me.
I'll never leave your side again.
[somber music playing]
Lily Cruz.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] Hello, Colonel.
I want you to hunt down Lily Cruz
and make sure that woman
can never cross me again.
I want her dead, as in yesterday!
Do you understand me?
Yes, Governor.
[tense music playing]
Ivy Aguas is dead.
Lily Cruz is next.
-[tires screeching]
-[door opens]
Let's split up!
You! Over there!
[Julio] Once I've dealt with her,
we'll go after everyone else
who keeps giving us problems.
No one can stop us.
We will crush them like bugs!
You will see, Arnaldo.
You will see.
Check there.
On my signal.
[door opens, closes]
They aren't here.
Let's go.
There's no one out back.
[line ringing]
Boss, they're not here.
Keep looking.
It was the right decision
to leave the co-op.
Now, they're on the hunt for Lily Cruz.
This is getting too risky, Anna.
Now, I'm sure Julio Ardiente
knows how "Lily Cruz"
is a threat to him.
But this isn't news to us.
If your life was in danger before,
it's worse now.
We have to be extra careful.
But I don't like all this
hiding and waiting, Jepoy.
What's the point
if I'm just going
to hide here like a coward?
Anna, you're not alone.
We're in this together.
You have to understand that this
is what we're supposed to do.
Just have faith that we'll send each
and every one of those Ardientes
to where they deserve.
That's a promise.
You know, I understand Miss Camia now.
Now I know how she feels
every time you tell her
to stay put and hide.
I heard the governor's
hunting Lily Cruz down.
If he finds her, I'm sure
he won't let her get out alive.
Don't worry, Vice Governor. Lily's safe.
And it's all according to plan.
You can't tell me about your plans, right?
Vice, I need you to trust in me.
Easy for you to say.
But how am I supposed to trust you
if you yourself don't trust me?
We reached out to you precisely
because you can be trusted.
And you're in the legal position
to determine the future
of this province and its people.
So, please, Vice.
Please understand
that I can't tell you everything
because there's too much at stake.
Let's just hope we don't fail.
[tense music playing]
This could be our last chance
to save this place.
Looking for something? What do you need?
We're out of food, Jepoy.
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
But it's already lunchtime.
You heard me, right?
I have to take care of something.
I'll buy food later.
There's a store right outside, Jepoy.
Yeah, I'll buy them later.
Just let me take care of this first.
Don't go out, okay? It's dangerous.
[phone ringing]
Hold on.
[suspenseful music playing]
Thank you.
You know what, Jaguar?
Until now, Papa's
still playing games with me.
Well, I have a hunch…
that Julio wasn't really
the one who saved you.
[scoffs] You know, what?
You're just saying that
because you hate him.
You're too quick to forget, Emilia.
Don't forget everything
Julio's done to you.
How he disowned you.
Jaguar, I can still remember everything.
I was there. I saw it all.
By the way, what's the news
on that Mercedes Palacio?
As of now, it's a dead end.
But, rumor has it…
that it was Julio who
wanted to hunt down Lily Cruz.
[groans]
What if she was the one who rescued you?
That's impossible, Jaguar.
Lily Cruz doesn't have the wits
or the resources to do that.
I can even bet you my
multimillion jewelry collection
that she couldn't have done it.
No, it's not her.
It's impossible that she was
the one who helped me.
Hmm… Tricky.
Miss, I'll have three cans of sardines
and three packs of noodles.
Here you go.
That's too much.
I don't have enough change.
Sorry, but this is all I have.
[man] Give me a pack of cigarettes, miss.
[tense music playing]
Miss, you forgot your change!
Boss, I think I just saw Lily Cruz.
I'm here at District Sta. Ines.
Roger that. I'll follow her.
[man] Hold it right there,
miss! Are you Lily Cruz?
[tense music playing]
Lily Cruz.
Where do you think you're going?
There's no escape now.
Grab her.
-What's that way?
-An abandoned mansion.
Follow her.
[Jose] Get her.
[goon] Hurry.
-[gunshots]
-[Anna yelping]
Hey!
[goon] Hey! Stop!
[exhales sharply]
You got some nerve.
You had to make me run.
But, don't worry.
Later on, we'll be running into you.
You're disgusting!
I'd much rather die!
Die?
All right. What are you going to do now?
Jump off this cliff?
Or get shot?
Well?!
[suspenseful music playing]
Follow her. Find her.
[tense music playing]
Boss, it's too steep. I don't
think she survived the jump.
[Jose] Make sure.
I think she's dead too.
She's probably at the bottom.
[gunshots]
[phone ringing]
Hello, Governor?
Colonel, is Lily Cruz still alive?
She's dead, Governor.
Is that so?
You're sure she's dead?
She fell off a cliff.
Yes, Governor.
Good job.
[tense music playing]
[whispers] Anna.
Anna!
Come on. Jump.
Auntie?
Diego.
Did you hear the news
about Anna and Jepoy?
I did.
Thank God they're back at the safe house.
Uh, how was your meeting
with the vice governor?
He still doesn't believe we'll succeed.
But I have high hopes
that the vice governor won't let us down.
How about the evidence
you gathered with Atty. Fisher?
I'll go to Manila later
and bring the evidence
we collected to Secretary Martel.
I have to go, Aunt Camia.
Be careful, Diego.
Don't worry, Aunt Camia.
I'll do whatever it takes
to finish Lily's fight.
We can do this.
I never doubted that, Diego.
Not once.
[soft music playing]
Lily Cruz is dead.
Another one bites the dust.
[Julio chuckles]
[grunts]
Those bastards thought
they could get to me…
because of what they did to you,
and what they did to Emilia.
Ha!
That's where they were wrong.
They just made me more focused
and reignited the fire I had…
when I was a young man.
[Julio scoffs]
These stupid fools
just made me feel younger.
Now, you.
You.
It's time for you
to wake up from your slumber.
Don't forget…
my blood runs through your veins.
The blood of a king.
Blood that boils when someone
threatens to steal our throne.
Don't forget the people
who did this to you.
Use that hate…
so that you may rise, sit,
and rule by my side once again.
Use that hate.
Feel that hate.
Keep that hate burning!
Come back to me, my dear young prince.
I await your return.
[tense music playing]
HAPPY CENTENNIAL,
POBLACION ARDIENTE!
[woman] Don't forget to attend
the centennial celebration
of our province with
Governor Julio Ardiente!
There will be lots of food!
Don't forget to attend
the centennial celebration
of our province with
Governor Julio Ardiente!
Make me gorgeous, Dylan, okay?
[uplifting music playing]
I love it!
[Patricia] Madam!
-Hey, Patricia.
-Here's your gown.
It's beautiful! Just like you!
[Emilia] Perfect.
This is gonna be so fab and beautiful.
-So what's this about?
-This is from the governor.
[foreboding music playing]
[chuckles]
Please tell Governor Ardiente
that I'm looking forward
to his celebration.
-Will do, Commissioner.
-Okay. Thank you.
Jenny, where is my clutch bag?
Faster! Faster!
[groans]
What?
You look great.
Wow, Raul.
Your flattery could use more work.
You know, your vocabulary is still so…
[Emilia yelps]
[sensual music playing]
Oh, please!
Don't ruin this day.
Opportunist.
But you liked it.
Jenny, my clutch bag! My god!
Come on.
And wipe that smile off your face.
[marching band playing]
[cheers, applause]
[marching band stops]
Good morning, everyone.
Fellow citizens, my children, friends…
thank you for joining us…
in paying tribute to my dear Esmeralda.
You know…
before my beloved wife departed…
she told me that she worried most…
for her fellow citizens in this province.
Esmeralda truly loved you.
So she entrusted your welfare to me.
No matter what happens,
I will always take care of you.
[applause]
So, today, as we celebrate…
our province's centennial,
in front of Esmeralda's grave,
I want her to know…
that I kept my promise
and fulfilled her will…
to care for Ardiente's citizens.
And I will continue to do so
for as long as I live.
[applause]
-We love you!
-Long live the Ardientes!
-[pensive music playing]
-[man shouts indistinctly]
Esmeralda was not your real mother.
Who is my real mother, Papa?
And why are you keeping it from me?
Emilia.
Hi, Mama. Are you there?
Okay.
You see, Mama, it's so sad.
You're gone. You left us so early.
It's a shame.
We could've had girl talks together.
But, oh well.
You were gone too soon.
I miss you, Mama.
Citizens of Ardiente!
We shall continue our celebration
of our province's one-hundredth year!
[applause]
[marching band playing]
-[man] Governor, we love you!
-[supporters shout indistinctly]
[host] Let's all give a warm
round of applause
for the Ardiente family!
-Viva Ardiente!
Black is out!
Gold is in.
Ivy Aguas is dead.
But Lily Cruz is very much alive!
[indistinct chatter]
I am indestructible.
[theme music playing]